Why do British people pronounce words so
differently?
>> Like which words?
>> Like for instance, tomato. Is it tomato
like the Americans or tomato or tomato?
>> I mean in the UK it's usually tomato.
>> Tomato. Okay. And what about water? I
say water. Do other people say it
differently?
>> Yeah, I think so. In the UK at least the
water becomes soft so it sounds more
like water.
>> Water.
>> Okay. And are all the accents in the UK
the same everywhere?
>> No, definitely not. So someone from
Manchester and someone from London sound
very different.
>> Okay. And would you be able to
understand someone from somewhere else
in the UK?
>> Uh sometimes. It depends on how strong
the accent is. Sometimes if it's a
really strong accent even the locals
struggle to understand it.
>> Oh really? That makes me feel better.
>> Yeah. Well, you know, communication is
more about getting your message across
rather than perfection.
>> Mhm.
>> Learning English can be fun. If you want
to learn with us and you're a Mandarin
speaker, why not start with our British
accent course? That takes you through
the fundamentals of the British accent
step-by-step so you can speak with a
beautiful British accent.